原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
翻译      伊森泽生 Funky 子V
翻译      杏仁斯嘉丽  苏葵  河边
翻译      HenryMa  527泡芙  Eunice
校对       Eunice
时间轴      想念Gallifrey的Wholock  壬虚浪影
时间轴      树  Caroline
后期      雷鸣
总监      Eunice
蝴蝶梦
昨晚  我又梦到我去了曼陀丽庄园
Last night, I dreamt I went to Manderley again.
我梦到曾经作为车道的地方
I dreamt that where our drive once lay,
现在都长成了黑暗又扭曲的丛林
a dark and tortured jungle grew.
大自然吞噬了一切  但那栋房子依然矗立着
Nature had come into her own and yet the house still stood.
曼陀丽庄园
Manderley.
一如既往地隐秘和寂静
Secretive and silent as it had always been.
死而复生
Risen from the dead.
跟所有做梦的人一样  我可以穿越记忆的重重迷雾
Like all dreamers, I was allowed to pass through my memory.
像一座桥一样跨过漫长的岁月
Spanning the years like a bridge.
回到在蒙特卡洛的那个夏天
Back to that summer in Monte Carlo
彼时的我懵懂无知  前景渺茫
when I knew nothing and had no prospects.
你是说8块钱吗
Did you say eight?
8块钱  没错
Huit. Yes.
谢谢
Merci.
-再见  -再见
- Au revoir. - Au revoir.
我可以清晰地看到当年的那个女孩
I can see the girl I was so clearly,
即便我已经认不出她来了
even if I no longer recognize her.
我很好奇
And I wonder
如果没有范·霍珀夫人  我的人生会是怎样的
what my life would have been without Mrs. Van Hopper.
如果没有那份工作
Without that job.
想想甚是有趣  我的整个人生经历
Funny to think that the course of my existence
像一根线一样悬于她的好奇心上
hung like a thread upon her curiosity.
如果不是她  我永远不可能去曼陀丽庄园
If it wasn't for her, I would never have gone to Manderley...
也永远不会认识你
and would never have met you.
范·霍珀夫人
Mrs. Van Hopper.
你怎么耽搁了这么久
What kept you?
很抱歉  我不得不在邮局等一个包裹 我...
I'm sorry. I had to wait for a package at the post office. I...
我觉得是您的外甥寄来的
I believe it's from your nephew.
大概是他跟那个令人讨厌的女孩的蜜月旅行照吧
Oh, photographs of his honeymoon with that ghastly girl, I imagine.
打开吧
Open it.
在楼下准备好餐桌享用午餐
Get a table downstairs for lunch.
好的  照旧是1点钟吗
Yes. One o'clock as usual?
-就现在  我刚看见迈克西姆·德温特了  -好吧
- Now. I've just seen Maxim de Winter. - Oh, right.
看上去  心里的伤痛依然没有抚平
Still heartbroken, by the look of it.
他是您的朋友吗
He's a friend of yours?
迈克西姆·德温特  曼陀丽庄园的主人
Maxim de Winter, owner of Manderley.
-那是全英国最奢华的住宅之一  -好吧
- One of the finest homes in England. - Oh, yes.
他妻子去年去世了  他迫切需要人陪伴
His wife died last year. He's in dire need of company.
让酒店领班安排他坐在我旁边
Have the maître d' seat him next to me.
你需要给人家小费
You'll have to tip.
说真的  我教了你这么多东西
Honestly, with everything I'm teaching you,
你应该付钱给我才对
you ought to be paying me.
-谢谢你  范·霍珀夫人  -蠢丫头
- Thank you, Mrs. Van Hopper. - Stupid girl.
-你好  -小姐
- Bonjour. - Mademoiselle.
还是坐范·霍珀夫人常坐的桌子吗
Madam Van Hopper's usual table?
是的  谢谢
Oh, yes, thank you. Merci.
不
Oh, no.
等等  抱歉  她想着
Wait, sorry. She was wondering
能不能安排一位姓德温特的先生坐她旁边
if a Mr. de Winter could sit with her.
-迈克西姆·德温特先生吗  -是的
- Monsieur Maxim de Winter? - Oui.
德温特先生想坐在哪里  得看他自己的意思
It is the choice of Mr. de Winter where he wishes to be seated.
是的  当然了
Oh, yes, of course.
谢谢
Merci.
抱歉  是不够吗  我这里还有
So sorry. Is that not enough? Um, here. I've got more.
天呐  真抱歉  先生
God, I'm so sorry, monsieur.
请稍等一下
Just one moment.
别那么做  我听说他是个非常粗鲁无礼的人
Don't do it. I've heard he's a terrible bore.
-什么  -那个姓德温特的家伙
- Excuse me? - This de Winter chap.
谢谢
Thank you.
德温特先生  这边请
Monsieur de Winter, please, this way.
要一打牡蛎
Des huîtres, une douzaine.
"Des huîtres, une douzaine."
迈克西姆·德温特
Maxim de Winter.
真是出人意料  我都不知道你在蒙特卡洛啊
Well, I never. I had no idea you were in Monte.
你务必跟我们同桌用餐
You must join us.
我是伊迪·范·霍珀  你应该记得我外甥比尔吧
Edie Van Hopper. I think you remember my nephew. Billy?
你去年秋天在布伦海姆见过他  全名是比尔·惠特尼
You met him at Blenheim last fall. Billy Whitney.
他大概跟我差不多高
He's about my height.
他的头发是黄色的  眼睛有点弱视
He's got sandy hair and he's got a bit of a lazy eye.
这样的人我怎么可能忘记呢
I can't imagine how I could've forgotten.
请代我向比尔问好
Do give my regards to Billy.
你知道吗
Oh, would you know?
他结婚了  对方是一个非常迷人的姑娘
He's married, and to the most enchanting girl.
-是吗  真好  -他寄来照片了
- Is he? Good. - He sent photographs.
我可以拿给你看
I'm going to show them to you.
-过来  婚礼真的非常盛大  -我信你说的
- Come here. The wedding was divine. - I believe you,
但我还是希望独自享用午餐
but I prefer to lunch alone.
日安  范·霍珀小姐
Good day, Miss Van Hopper.
-不是的  -什么
- Oh, no. - What?
我们没有亲缘关系  她就是个员工
We're not related. She's staff.
或许可以称她为我的看护
Well, I mean, I guess you could call her my ward.
好的  明白  失陪了
I see. Now, if you'll excuse me.
亲爱的  不如你去把照片拿过来吧
Darling, why don't fetch those photographs?
-我相信德温特先生一定很想看看  -好的
- I'm sure Mr. de Winter would love to see them. - Yes.
不  真的  拜托  别麻烦了
No, please, please, please. Don't trouble yourself.
-没必要拿  -亲爱的  一点都不麻烦
- It's unnecessary. - Oh, my precious, it's no trouble at all!
一点都不麻烦  去吧  快
Not at all. Go along. Quickly.
没事的  她很快就会下来了
No, no. She'll be down in a jiffy.
接下来是我最喜欢的部分
No, this is my favorite part.
我叫她去把照片取下来
I asked her to go and get the photographs,
她从桌子边飞快地冲出去
and she darts from the table,
然后她就走了  半天没回来
and then she's gone. Doesn't come back.
我想着  "天呐  别告诉我她开始画画了"
I thought, "Oh, God, don't tell me she started sketching."
-不  她真的是个小画家  -天呐
- Oh, no, no, she's an artist. - Oh, my!
总之  她后来又跑下来了
Anyway, she comes running back down,
浑身散发着浓浓的廉价玫瑰水味
reeking of cheap rose water.
那气味可真是熏死人
I mean, the smell of it!
只要有一个黄金单身汉
Show me an eligible bachelor
就会涌现一屋子
and I will show you a room
失心疯一般的女人
full of women acting like they've lost their minds.
太迟了
It's too late.
-抱歉  -没事  坐下吧
- Sorry. - Never mind, sit down.
竟说我们有亲缘关系  想想看多离谱
Related. I mean, imagine.
我以前很爱曼陀丽庄园的舞会  非常奢华迷人
I loved the Manderley ball. It was just so glamorous.
但自从悲剧发生后  就再也没举办过了
I suppose that's all stopped since the tragedy.
竟然发生了那种事  真叫人震惊
Such a shocking thing that happened.
-要如何解释啊  -太可怕了
- How do you explain it? - Awful.
他那时深爱着她
He adored her!
他的吕蓓卡
His Rebecca.
早上好  范·霍珀夫人
Morning, Mrs. Van Hopper.
范·霍珀夫人
Mrs. Van Hopper?
您没事吧
Are you all right?
我想吐  我想吐
I'm sick. I'm sick.
我  我吐了一晚上了
I'm... I was sick all night.
-快  快叫医生来  -好的
- Call the... call the medecin. - Okay.
-立刻叫医生过来  -好的
- Call them right now. The doctor. - All right.
桶在哪儿  桶在哪儿
Where is the bucket? Where's the bucket?
我去拿桶  来  我拿着呢
I'll get the bucket! Here, I've got it.
你在等夫人吗
You are waiting for madame?
不  她病了  医生叫她好好休息
Oh, no. She's unwell. The doctor told her to rest.
所以今天只有我一个人
So, it's just me today.
这是不行的  露台只允许贵客享用
It is not possible. The terrace is for guests only.
但我是夫人的同伴
But I'm a lady's companion...
当真吗
Really?
是的  员工是不能使用的
Yes, it is not for staff.
先生  这位年轻小姐可以和我坐在一起
Monsieur? The young lady will be joining me.
再安排个座位吧
Set another place, please.
当然没问题  德温特先生
Bien sûr, Monsieur de Winter.
不  我无法承认这般盛情
No, please. I couldn't possibly.
没事的
It's absolutely fine.
并且如果我们不想聊天  也可以不说话
And we needn't talk unless we feel like it.
你  你不必为我这样的
You... you didn't have to do that.
我的动机其实很自私
My motives were entirely selfish.
这是昨天的报纸  我都已经看过了
This is yesterday's paper. I've already read it.
谢谢您的好意
Thank you. It's very kind.
你这工作都做些什么
So, what is it you do for...
我算是"贵妇伴侣"
I'm what's called "a lady's companion."
如果贵妇需要出钱才能有伴
If a lady has to pay for company,
那说明这位贵妇挺差劲的  不是吗
that says something about the lady, doesn't it?
可以点餐了吗
May I take your order?
一打牡蛎
Des huîtres, une douzaine.
早餐吃这个吗
For breakfast?
按你听到的上  再续点咖啡
You heard her. Et encore du café.
好的  德温特先生  小姐
Bien, Monsieur de Winter. Mademoiselle.
请恕我冒昧  为何非得选择她
If it's not rude, why her?
感觉你似乎
Seems like you would
给很多人当伴侣都会非常出色
make an excellent companion for any number of people.
但我一直很喜欢到处旅行
But I've always wanted to travel,
除此之外  每年还有90镑的薪水
so there's that, and £90 a year.
我知道这些钱对你来说不算什么
I know that doesn't seem very much to you,
但对我来说已经很多了
but it's a lot to me.
这样看的话  孤独大概的确是有价格的吧
I suppose you can set a price on loneliness.
很奇怪  不是吗  有些人独自一人似乎也过得很好
It's odd, isn't it? Some people seem perfectly happy alone
但有些人却需要别人陪着一起度过
while others just need someone to pass the time with.
那个人是谁都没关系
Doesn't matter who.
你是哪种
Which are you?
我父母都已经去世了  所以...
Well, my parents are dead, so...
我习惯了独自一人
I'm used to being alone.
你的早餐来了
Here comes your breakfast.
请慢用  一打牡蛎
Et voilà. Une douzaine d'huîtres.
我一直都想尝尝  所以...
I've always wanted to try them, so...
趁着还新鲜  快尝尝
Try them before they get warm.
太谢谢你了  感觉我从没说过这么多话
Thank you so much. I don't think I've ever spoken so much in my entire life.
说得很精彩
It was very impressive.
-抱歉我还点了牡蛎...  -不  没事的
- And I'm sorry about the oysters, too. I... - No, that was fine.
非常谢谢你  我...
Thank you very much. I...
我很久都没那么开心过了
I haven't enjoyed myself like that for quite a long time.
再见
À bientôt.
有人在吗
Hello?
-前台有张字条给您  -谢谢  夫人身体不适
- A note from the front desk. - Merci. Madame's indisposed.
-我会转交给她的  -是给您的  小姐
- I'll take it to her. - It's for you, mademoiselle.
谢谢
Merci.
是什么事
What do they want?
迈克西姆·德温特
一起去兜风
是前台  他们...
It was just the front desk, they were...
想知道您怎么样了
wondering how you are.
你是怎么脱身的
So how did you escape?
我说我要上网球课
I said I had a tennis lesson.
她一直念叨我该增进球技
She's been on at me to improve my game.
真狡猾
Sneaky.
-你想去哪里  -哪里都可以
- So where do you want to go? - Anywhere is fine.
你肯定有想看看的地方吧
There must be somewhere you want to see.
就是有点远
Well, it's quite far.
不错  正好呼吸新鲜空气
Good. I could use the fresh air.
这是辆3.5升宾利吗
Is this a 3.5-liter Bentley?
没错  你怎么会这么了解车
It is. How do you know so much about cars?
是我父亲  他生前很喜欢车
Oh, my father, he loved them.
能否问一下  你的双亲是什么时候去世的
If I may ask, when did your parents pass away?
两年前  死于流感
Two winters ago. Influenza.
我母亲死于流感  我父亲...
Well, my mother died of influenza, and my...
四天后也去了
father died just four days later.
你觉得会有人死于心碎吗
Do you think a person could die of a broken heart?
-我说话欠考虑了  对不起  -没事
- That was thoughtless of me. I'm sorry. - No.
没事的
It's all right.
这才叫兜风
All part of the plan.
异国植物园
其实有棵仙人掌  原长于墨西哥
There's actually a cactus, it's native to Mexico,
能长到65英尺高
and it grows to 65 feet tall.
可以活200年  但从第70年起才能开花
It lives for 200 years, but it doesn't flower until it's 70.
你都是从哪里学到这些的
Where do you learn this stuff?
从某处读来的  我知道的一切都来自书本
I read about it somewhere. Everything I know is from books.
我还没见过什么大世面
I haven't really experienced anything yet.
但我打算趁年轻好好经历一下
I plan to before I'm old.
看
Look!
你来过这里吗
Have you been here before?
很多年前  度蜜月时来过
Years ago. On my honeymoon.
-你夫人是怎么  -拜托  别说这个了
- How did your wife... - Please... let's not.
德温特先生
Mr. de Winter.
-去开吧  -不行  我不能开
- Go on. - Oh, no. I couldn't.
你可以的  你会开不是吗
Yes. Yes, you can. You know how, don't you?
会是会  可我...
Well, yes, I...
很好  只要不是从书上学的就好
Well, good. As long as you didn't learn from a book.
能和我说说曼陀丽庄园吗  听说那里很美
Will you tell me about Manderley? I hear it's beautiful.
的确很美
It is. Yeah.
曼陀丽不只是座宅邸  它是我生活的全部
Manderley, it's more than a house. It's my life.
几个世纪来都是由父辈把它传给子辈
It's been passed from father to son and father to son for centuries.
至少延续至今
Until now, anyway.
如果我无后而终  就要交由我姐姐继承
You see, if I die without an heir, it goes to my sister.
她的儿子们都是好孩子  只不过不姓德温特
And her sons are nice boys, but they're just not de Winters.
我们到了
There we go.
谢谢你让我们安全到达了
Well, thank you for getting us home safely.
别忘了拿好你的东西
Don't forget your things.
先生  能请你帮个忙吗
Sir, would you give us a hand?
异国植物园
《爱情诗选集》
我需要你帮我做这个
This is what I need from you.
请你抓着棚盖  和我同时抬起来
Would you grab that bag and just lift at the same time?
一  二  三
One, two, three.
吕蓓卡赠迈克斯
请你放回去
Put that back, please.
好的  对不起...
Yes, of course. I'm sorry. I...
钥匙留给停车员就好  晚安
Leave the keys with the valet. Good night.
晚安
Good night.
你回来了
Hello.
护士一小时前就走了
The nurse left an hour ago.
网球教练只剩晚上有免费课
The tennis coach only had a late session free...
我在那练习发球
and I was practicing my serve.
摸黑上网球课吗
A tennis lesson in the dark?
是的
Yes.
迈克斯赠吕蓓卡  吕蓓卡赠迈克斯
Rebecca from Max. Max from Rebecca.
你这傻丫头  为什么要看他的私人书本
You stupid girl. Why would I look at his personal book?
给您的  是德温特先生留的
For you. From Monsieur de Winter.
迈克西姆·德温特
去卡普代享用午餐吗
给我的吗  谢谢
Pour moi? Merci.
-我要走了  -你穿的什么衣服
- I'm off. - What have you got on?
我都能看见里面了
I can see right through it.
-你穿内衣了吧  -当然
- You wearing any undergarments? - Yes, of course.
迈克西姆·德温特
去摩纳哥城散步吗
我想画那些漂亮的房子
I'm trying to paint those beautiful houses.
你用不着网球拍  好了
Actually, you don't need your tennis racket. All right.
小姐
Mademoiselle.
谢谢
Merci.
-你在做什么  -你马上就知道了
- What are you doing? - Oh, you'll see.
想象一下  如果能把回忆像香水一样装进瓶子
Imagine if you could bottle a memory like scent.
你想开启它  就能随时开启它
Then, whenever you wanted, you could open it.
就好像把那一瞬重新度过
It'd be like living the moment all over again.
在你如此年轻的生命里
And what particular moments
你想把哪些瞬间装进瓶子
in your young life would you bottle?
这个星期  此时此刻  每一分钟
This week. Now. Every minute of it.
永远不会忘
Never forget it.
如果有不想要的回忆  就可以干脆丢掉
And any memories you didn't want, you could simply throw away.
"一起去兜风"
"Come for a drive."
"去卡普代享用午餐"
"Lunch at the Cap."
去海滩
The beach.
可我喜欢这里的海岸
But I love the coast down here.
真的好美
It's so beautiful.
有意思了
Oh, there we go!
你在看什么
What are you looking at?
-那个是...  -让我看看
- Um, well, it's... - Let me see.
如果我是你  我不会看的
No, I wouldn't if I were you.
不行  幸好你并不是我
No... Well, it's just as well you're not...
-对不起  -没关系
- Sorry. - That's all right.
走吧  我们去游泳
Come on. Let's go for a swim.
走吧  走吧
Come on. Come on!
-快下来  -不了
- Come in! - No!
-为什么不  -我不想下来
- Why not? - I don't want to!
你在怕什么
What are you afraid of?
水太冷  要冻坏了
It's too cold. No, it's freezing.
不冷  很舒服
No, it's not. It's lovely!
我能感觉得到  太冰了
I can feel it. It's freezing cold!
-你快过来  -不  我要去把香槟喝光
- You come here! - No. I'm gonna drink all the champagne.
我无所谓
I don't care!
天呐  瞧瞧你逼我做了什么
God! Look at what you're making me do.
你起来了
Oh, you're up.
我...
I, um...
你好转了真是太好了  护士呢
I'm so glad you're feeling better. Where's the nurse?
打发走了
Dismissed.
看你像是游过泳  打完网球后游的
Took a swim, I see. After tennis?
是的
Yes.
去吧  擦干头发  快去
Well, go on. Dry your hair. Chop-chop.
我们要下去吃晚餐吗
Are we going down for dinner?
我自己去
I am.
你可以安排前台服务生
You can see the concierge about
为我们订明天的早班火车票了
booking us on the early train tomorrow.
行李也可以开始打包了
And you can set about packing.
明天
Um, tomorrow?
比尔周六启航去纽约
Billy is sailing for New York on Saturday.
我们可以乘同一艘船
We can catch the same boat.
我在欧洲待得烦死了
I'm sick to death of Europe.
别这么失魂落魄地看着我
Don't look at me like a drowned rat.
你很快就能习惯纽约的生活
You'll get used to New York fast enough.
男人多得是  到处都新鲜
Plenty of boys and excitement.
而且都和你门当户对
All in your own class.
你真以为人们不会议论吗
Did you really think people wouldn't talk?
断了是好事
Oh, you're best out of it.
所有人都知道她去世后他差点疯了
Everyone knows he nearly lost his mind after she died.
不幸来得太突然了
It was all too sudden and tragic.
你不会真以为他爱上你了吧
Do you honestly think he is in love with you?
他只是拿你散散心  仅此而已
It was a distraction, dear. That's it.
我们要离开了  到纽约去
We'll go away. We'll go to New York.
你会找到你的出路的
You'll find your way.
你会把这一切都忘掉
You'll forget all about it.
相信我  你会把这一切都忘掉的
Trust me, you will forget all about it.
请等一下
Just a moment.
范·霍珀夫人要走了  我也必须离开
Mrs. Van Hopper is leaving and I have to go, too.
-你在说什么  -真的  就现在  今天就走
- What are you talking about? -Yes. Now. Today.
我就想跟你道个别
I just wanted to say goodbye.
你怎么没和我提过
Why haven't you told me before?
因为她昨晚才决定的
Because she only decided it last night.
我们要去巴黎  和她的外甥碰面
And we're going to Paris with... to meet her nephew.
然后去瑟堡乘船去纽约
Then we go to Cherbourg to sail to New York.
听我说  你别哭
All right. Listen, you mustn't cry.
给我一点时间想想
Just give me a moment to think.
我...
I...
我不能久留  她让我在楼下等
I can't stay long. She's expecting me downstairs.
跟我走吧
Come with me.
什么
What?
去曼陀丽庄园
To Manderley.
什么  当你的秘书吗
What? As your secretary?
不  不是
No. No.
当我的妻子
As my wife.
我这是在向你求婚  小傻瓜
I'm asking you to marry me, you little fool.
我不能去曼陀丽庄园
I can't come to Manderley.
你当然可以  你说过你想看看这世界
Yes, you can. You said you wanted to see the world.
曼陀丽就是这世上最美好的地方
Manderley is the best part of it.
她当然在大厅  不然能去哪里
Well, of course she's down there. Where else is she?
没错  我20分钟后就要出发去赶火车了
Yes, I've got to leave in 20 minutes to catch the train.
-我去跟她说  -真的要去吗
- I'll tell her. - Do we have to go?
不...当然要去了  其实我还挺想去会会她的
No, in fact... Yes, we do. I'm actually looking forward to this.
我等的就是这句话
That's exactly what I'm waiting for.
别担心
Now, don't worry.
又是谁啊
Who is this now?
这是我这辈子听到过的最好的消息
This is the most wonderful news I've ever heard in my life!
真想赶紧告诉我的朋友们  太不可思议了
Wait till I tell my friends, I can't believe it!
打算怎么安排婚事  拜托了  全都告诉我吧
What are the plans? Please. I must know everything.
都已经安排好了
Well, the plans are settled.
我们就在这里结婚  在欧洲度蜜月
We'll marry here, and honeymoon in Europe.
然后回家  回曼陀丽庄园
And then home to Manderley.
天呐
Oh, my goodness.
你这辈子还没听过这么浪漫的话吧
Have you ever heard of anything more romantic in your life?
"回曼陀丽庄园"
"Home to Manderley."
天呐  那可是童话故事里才有的
Oh, my goodness. It's out of a fairy tale.
好了  我先去打点一下
All right. I'll go and make sure
不然你的行李就要上火车了
your bags don't end up on the train.
-是要快点  -你没事的
- Do hurry. - You'll be fine.
快去吧  我们有太多事情要聊了
Yes, yes, go along. We have lots to talk about.
我的天呐  你动作还挺快啊
Well, goodness gracious, don't you work quickly?
你有做一些你不该做的事吗
Have you been doing things you shouldn't?
我不懂你在说什么
I don't know what you mean.
不过幸好你家人都不在了  不用向他们解释
Well, you don't have a family, luckily, to explain it to.
这事我就不管了
I wash my hands of it.
到了曼陀丽庄园  肯定会安排个工作给你
Gonna have your work cut out for you at Manderley.
老实说  我觉得你不能胜任
And, frankly, I don't think you're up to it.
-我可以学  -这么跟你说吧  亲爱的
- I can learn. - Let me tell you something, honey.
用性拴住男人很容易
When you trap a man between your legs,
但他们不会留恋
they don't stick around for long.
再见  范·霍珀夫人
Goodbye, Mrs. Van Hopper.
他娶你单纯是因为不想在那间老旧的大宅子里
He's only marrying you because he doesn't want to go on living
和她的鬼魂度过余生
in that big old house with her ghost!
我不相信有鬼魂
I don't believe in ghosts.
天呐  我最讨厌他们这一套了
Oh, God. I hate it when they do this.
就不能低调一点吗
So much for keeping things quiet.
你也知道她的  老爷
You know how she is, sir.
在曼陀丽有曼陀丽的规矩
There's a way things are done at Manderley.
亲爱的  这是弗里思
Darling, this is Frith.
你好
Hello.
我们还是正式一点吧  来  起来咯
Let's do things properly, shall we? There we go.
-你干什么呢  -怎么  你不喜欢啊
- What are you doing? - What? You don't like that?
上肩
Up you go.
别这样了  迈克斯  放我下来
Don't, Max, put me down.
丹弗斯太太
Mrs. Danvers.
欢迎来到曼陀丽庄园
Welcome to Manderley.
你好  见到你很高兴
Hello. It's a pleasure.
-谢谢  -茶泡好了
- Thank you. Thank you. - Tea is ready.
丹弗斯是这儿的管家
Danvers runs the house.
别怕  她没看起来那么吓人
Don't worry, she's not as scary as she seems.
迈克西姆  这里太棒了
Oh, Maxim, it's wonderful!
别吠了
Stop that.
游子可算回来了  见到你很高兴  迈克斯
There he is. The wanderer returns. Good to see you, Max.
-我也是  弗兰克  -旅途如何
- And you, Frank. - How was the trip?
结果还挺丰富多彩的
Was rather eventful, as it turns out.
-我是弗兰克·克劳利  德温特夫人  -幸会
- Frank Crawley, Mrs. de Winter. - It's a pleasure.
谢谢  你好
Thank you. Hello.
弗兰克是地产管理人
Frank's the estate manager.
这里没了他可就完蛋了
The place would fall apart without him.
他言过其实了  别听他的
Ah, no, no. He exaggerates. Ignore him.
我不想扫兴  但我有几份文件急需你签名
I, I hate to be a bore, but I urgently need a few signatures.
我保证只借走他一下  马上还给你
I promise I'll have him back to you in a jiffy.
-我们走吧  -好的
- Shall we? - Yes.
丹弗斯  带德温特夫人转一圈  好吗
Danvers, show Mrs. de Winter the house. Can you?
不用  没关系的  我等你
Oh, no, that's all right. I'll wait.
别犯傻了  去吧  我过会儿来找你
No, don't be silly. Go on. I'll catch you up.
这座庄园已经在这家族名下三百多年了
The estate has been in the family for over 300 years.
最初是亨利八世赠予的礼物
It was originally a gift from Henry VIII.
太非凡了
Extraordinary.
如果有客人来了  您可以用客厅招待
If there are guests, you may use the drawing room.
记得告诉弗里思  让他点燃炉火
Don't forget to tell Frith to light the fires,
不过一般来说  老爷喜欢
but generally, Mr. de Winter prefers
在书房这里喝咖啡
to take his coffee here in the library.
还好有你在  丹弗斯太太
Glad you're here, Mrs. Danvers. I'll...
不然我肯定记不住这一切
I'll Never remember all this.
吕蓓卡·德温特
弗兰克·克劳利先生
曼陀丽庄园
康沃尔
如果您担心的是这个  夫人
Oh, I'm sure you won't disappoint him, madam,
您一定不会让他失望的
if that's your concern.
德温特家族可追溯到都铎王朝
The de Winter family dates back to the Tudors.
那是谁
And, um, who's that?
那是卡罗琳·德温特  老爷的姑婆
That's Caroline de Winter. Mr. de Winter's great aunt.
她好妩媚动人
She's very striking.
是的  她可是英国第一批
Yes, and one of the first women
获得医生执照的女性之一
to qualify as a doctor in England.
这是其中一幅老爷最喜欢的画作
It's one of his favorites.
大家都睡在哪儿
Where does everyone sleep?
女仆睡阁楼  男仆睡地下室
Maids in the attic, men below stairs,
应该和你待过的地方一个规矩吧
just as in your other houses, I presume.
我从没见过这么壮观的大宅
Never even seen a house like this.
抱歉  我以为你当过贴身女仆呢
Oh, I'm sorry. I thought you'd been a lady's maid.
主卧现在搬到东厢了
The master bedroom is now in the east wing.
这花纹真好看
What a... pretty pattern.
这是克拉丽斯  在您的女仆来之前负责服侍您
This is Clarice. She'll look after you until your maid gets here.
我没有雇女仆  不过我自己能应付得过来
I don't have a maid, but I'm sure I'll manage without one.
你会需要一个的
Well, I think you'll find you need one.
那就让克拉丽斯来吧
Perhaps Clarice could take the position.
这里看不见大海
You can't see the sea from here.
是看不见
No, you can't.
如果老爷要他以前的衣橱
Should Mr. de Winter ask for his old wardrobe,
恐怕您得告诉他这里会放不下
I'm afraid you must tell him it wouldn't fit here.
住宅这一面的房间要小很多
The rooms on this side of the house are much smaller.
这里以前不是他的卧室吗
This wasn't his bedroom before?
不是的  德温特夫人的房间都在西厢
No, no, no. No. Mrs. de Winter's rooms were in the west wing.
这里多好啊  空着太可惜了
Well, it's a lovely room. Much too nice to stand empty.
客房都不会空闲太久的
The guest rooms are never empty for very long.
德温特夫人还在世时  我们办过很多次宴会
We did a lot of entertaining when the late Mrs. de Winter was alive.
曼陀丽舞会在当时可是件大事
The Manderley ball was quite an event.
我就让克拉丽斯陪您了
I'll leave you with Clarice.
问我个问题
Ask me a question.
什么问题
What sort of question?
什么都行
Anything.
我对你毫无保留
I have no secrets from you.
既然我们结婚了  难道不应该坦诚相待吗
Don't you think that's how it should be now that we're married?
所有的婚姻都隐藏着秘密
All marriages have their secrets.
如果你愿意  可以和我说说她
You can talk to me about her... if you want.
晚安  亲爱的
Good night, darling.
迈克西姆
Maxim?
别碰他
Leave him.
叫醒梦游的人很危险
It's dangerous to wake a sleepwalker.
不用担心  但马厩需要翻修屋顶
And nothing to worry about, but the stables will need reroofing
因为瓦片都腐烂了
because the tiles are spoiled...
-早上好  亲爱的  -早上好
- Good morning, darling. - Good morning.
-睡得怎么样  -挺好的
- Sleep well? - Yes, not bad.
来
Come.
-您适应得如何  -非常好  谢谢
- How are you settling in? - Very well, thank you.
那就好  那就好
Good. Good.
那我去上面等您
I'll... see you up there, shall I?
-我马上就来  -再见  德温特夫人
- Won't be a sec. - Mrs. de Winter.
再见  克劳利先生
Mr. Crawley.
叫我弗兰克就好
Frank. It's Frank.
我该早点起床的
I should have got up earlier.
-我们就能共用早餐了  -没关系
- We could have had breakfast together. - Oh, that's all right.
你知道你会梦游吗
Did you know you sleepwalk?
好好享用早餐吧
Enjoy your breakfast.
杰斯珀
Jasper!
你要去哪儿  杰斯珀
Where are you going? Jasper!
杰斯珀  你跑去哪了
Jasper, where have you gone?
吕
曼陀丽庄园宾客名册
克罗斯比与福克斯内衣坊
假面舞会
抱歉打扰各位...
I'm sorry to disturb you all...
克拉丽斯  你看见老爷了吗
Clarice, have you seen Mr. de Winter?
你有药膏吗  我割伤手了
And do you have a plaster? I've cut my hand.
让我看看
Let me see.
-没什么大碍  我没事  -天呐  等一下
- Really, it's nothing. I'm fine. - Oh, my. One moment.
正好你在  夫人
Since you're here, madam,
请问今天的菜单是不是合意
may I have your approval for today's menus?
好  非常合适  我完全满意
Yes. Good. Very suitable. Very nice indeed.
-烤小牛肉的酱汁呢  -那款看起来非常好
- And the sauce for the roast veal? - Yes, that looks excellent.
不  我空着没填
No, but I've left it blank, you see?
德温特夫人非常讲究酱汁
Mrs. de Winter was most particular about her sauces.
好  那...
Right. Well, um...
就按德温特夫人的喜好来吧  谢谢
We'll have whatever Mrs. de Winter would have had. Thank you.
好的  夫人
Very well, madam.
-好了  -非常感谢
- There we go. - Thank you very much.
吕
你还好吗  亲爱的
Is everything all right, darling?
我想从伦敦订一些新内衣
I was thinking of... ordering some new undergarments from London.
带蕾丝的内衣  还要一套睡衣
Something lacy and a nightgown.
我什么时候抱怨过你的穿着
When have I ever complained about what you wear?
这样真好  对吧  你我二人世界
This is nice, isn't it? Just us.
就好像回到了度蜜月的时候
It's almost like we're back on our honeymoon.
我好怀念啊  你呢
Oh, I miss it. Don't you?
开车兜风  四处探索  小咖啡馆
Driving, the exploring, little cafes?
看到旧旧的旅馆就住下
Seeing some funny old hotel and just staying there.
那不是真实生活  亲爱的
That's not real life, darling.
-杰斯珀  杰斯珀  -我去追
- Jasper! Jasper! - I'll get him.
别管它  它能找到回来的路
No, just leave him. He'll find his own way back.
太陡峭了  万一它掉下去呢
It's so steep. What if he falls?
我说了别管它
I said leave him!
杰斯珀
Jasper!
杰斯珀  过来
Jasper, come here!
杰斯珀
Jasper!
杰斯珀  快出来
Jasper, come out of there.
杰斯珀  过来
Jasper, come here.
好了  找条绳子把你拴上
All right, get something to tie you with.
"我归来"号
有人吗
Hello?
这里什么都没有  小傻瓜
There's nothing here, silly.
我...
I'm...
我不知道这里还住人
I didn't realize that anyone lived here.
我不住这儿  我住在看守人的小屋
No, I don't, do I? Live up in the keeper's cottage.
我从上午就一直在挖贝壳
I've been digging for shells since forenoon.
你也在挖贝壳吗
Oh, you've been digging for shells? Huh?
没有  我...
No. I just, I...
我需要条绳子拴狗
I needed something to tie my dog with.
我马上就不打扰你了
I'll be out of your way in a moment.
-它又不是你的狗  -对  不是
- He ain't yourn. - Oh, no.
-是德温特先生的  -不
- He's Mr. de Winter's dog. - No.
是她的狗
That's her dog.
她不再来这里了
She don't come here no more.
她掉进海里了  对吧
She... she gone into the sea, ain't she?
淹死了
She drowned.
你不像她
You ain't like her.
是  来吧  杰斯珀
Yes. Come on, Jasper.
我什么都没说
I never said nothin', did I?
来吧  杰斯珀  走吧
Come on, Jasper. Come on.
我知道你为什么不想来这边了
I know why you didn't want to come down here.
我怎么知道
How am I supposed to know?
你什么都不说  我怎么知道
How am I supposed to know anything if you don't tell me?
-那里本来应该锁上  -有人在里面
- That's supposed to be locked. - There was someone in there.
很可能是看守人的儿子  贝恩  他与世无争
Probably just the keeper's son, Ben. He's harmless enough.
迈克西姆  我...
Maxim, I...
天呐
Oh, God!
-那是在意大利时  -瞧瞧他
- That's in Italy. - There he is.
对  那是婚礼刚刚结束时拍的
Oh, yes. That was just after the wedding.
这条纯色连衣裙真漂亮
What a nice plain frock.
迈克斯说得对  你跟我想象中完全不一样
Look, Max was right. You're not at all what I expected.
你看着好些了  老头子
And you're looking better, old man.
没那么憔悴了
Not so drawn.
-我哪有  -胡说八道
- Please. - Bosh!
大家都知道你六个月前有多么失魂落魄
Everyone knows you were a perfect wreck six months ago.
给  奶奶  你看过这些照片吗
Here, Granny, have you seen these?
是不是很好看
Look, aren't they lovely?
-天呐  -嗯
- Goodness! - Yes.
这些是我们婚礼上拍的
So, these were from our wedding.
我听说你不打猎是怎么回事
What's all this I hear about you not hunting?
对  我不会骑马
Oh, no, I'm afraid I don't ride.
不会骑马怎么行  你会错失很多乐趣的
Oh, but you must! Or you'll miss out on all the fun.
来跟我们住吧  我教你
Come and stay. I can teach you.
她是全郡最厉害的女骑士了
You won't find a finer horsewoman in the county.
别说了  贾尔斯
Do dry up, Giles.
我姐姐发现她觉得有趣的事
Yes, it might shock my sister to learn
并不会引起所有人共鸣  会很震惊的
that not everyone shares her idea of fun.
不管她觉得什么有趣  她都理应好好玩玩
Well, whatever her idea of fun, she certainly deserves to have some.
事实上  我在考虑恢复办舞会
Well, actually, I've been thinking I might revive the ball.
这主意真不错
What a marvelous idea.
我们没谈过这个
That's not something we discussed.
别那么扫兴
Oh, don't be so damn miserable.
你以前很喜欢的
You used to love it.
你可以为你的新娘办一场
You can hold it in honor of your new bride.
好吧
Fine.
那就这么定了
Well, that's settled, then.
-敬我们的新女主人  -敬新女主人
- To our new hostess. - Yeah. To our new hostess.
你要在曼陀丽庄园暂住吗  亲爱的
Are you staying at Manderley, dear?
-她就在这生活  -不
- She lives here. - Oh, no.
-记得吗  奶奶  -奶奶  我们给你介绍过的
- Remember, Granny? - Granny, we introduced you.
她是迈克西姆的妻子
She's Maxim's wife.
她才不是
No, she is not.
她不是迈克西姆的妻子
She's not Maxim's wife.
多么愚蠢的想法
What a silly notion.
办舞会真是个好主意
Well, it's... good news about the ball, uh...
太久没办了
It's been far too long.
我不记得你
I don't remember you.
不  我...
Oh, no, I...
我们之前没见过
We haven't met before.
迈克西姆  这孩子是谁
Maxim, who is this child?
天呐  好吧  带奶奶回家吧
Oh, Christ. All right, let's get Granny home now.
你对吕蓓卡做了什么
What have you done with Rebecca?
-你别管  -不  我来
- Leave it. - No, I've got it!
我要见吕蓓卡
I want to see Rebecca.
-别碰我  -她就是有点...
- Please, leave me alone! - She just gets a little...
每天的这个时候  再加上这天气...
it's the time of day, and the weather...
-天呐  -我就想...
- Oh, my! - I just want to...
让她上车
Get her in the car.
我把她抱进车里  你去跟她说
I'll put her in the car. You go and talk to her.
我们上车吧  奶奶  来
Listen, let's get in the car, Granny. Come on.
这是从花房拿的  希望可以
This is from the flower room. I hope that's all right.
-谢谢  -对不起
- Thank you. - Look, I apologize.
我忘记奶奶有多喜欢吕蓓卡了
I'd forgotten how fond our grandmother was of Rebecca.
我没事
I'm fine.
她就是那么气人
She was just one of those bloody annoying people.
每个人都无法抗拒她
Irresistible to everybody.
无论是男人  女人  孩子  还是动物
The men, women, children, animals.
我们这些凡人根本没法比
Us mere mortals couldn't hope to compete.
-老爷  -他哭什么
- Sir. - Why is he crying?
老爷  晨室里
Sir, one of the porcelain pieces
有一件瓷器不见了
is missing from the morning room,
现在丹弗斯太太要开除这个男孩
and now Danvers is calling for the boy's dismissal.
-但不是...  -哪一件
- But it wasn't... - Which piece?
我们不确定  老爷
We're not sure, sir.
丹弗斯太太
Danvers!
-没什么事吧  -没事
- Is everything all right? - Yes, it's fine.
晨室里有样东西不见了
Something rather's just gone missing from the morning room.
仅此而已
That's all.
-丹弗斯太太  -什么东西不见了
- Danvers! - What is it? What's gone missing?
你为什么觉得是罗伯特拿的
What on earth makes you think Robert took it?
德累斯顿瓷器非常值钱  老爷
The Dresden is extremely valuable, sir.
-不是我干的  -单那一件就价值一百多镑
- But it wasn't me! - That piece alone is worth £100.
-老爷  不太可能是...  -那是谁干的  弗里思
- Sir, I find it most unlikely... - Then who, Frith?
干杂活的女仆是不能进晨室的  我负责收拾
The between maid isn't allowed in the morning room. I do it.
德温特夫人还在世的时候  我们一起收拾瓷器
When Mrs. de Winter was alive, we did it together.
-弗里思只是说...  -是我
- All Frith is saying... - It was me.
是我打碎的  它碎了
I broke it. It broke.
我不小心打碎的  它掉到地上了
It was an accident. It fell.
好了  真相大白
Well, there we go.
罗伯特  你没事了
Robert, you're off the hook.
碎片在哪儿  夫人
Where are the pieces, madam?
在后面的书桌抽屉里
In the bureau drawer at the back.
寄到伦敦去  丹弗斯太太  看能不能修补
Send them to London, Danvers. See if anything can be done.
没问题  老爷
Certainly, sir.
如果再发生这种事
And may I suggest, should anything like this happen again,
德温特夫人能不能直接告诉我
that Mrs. de Winter tell me herself.
都没事了吧
If we're all quite finished?
吕
弗兰克
Oh, Frank.
德温特夫人
Mrs. de Winter.
我还以为你跟迈克斯去伦敦了
I thought you'd gone up to London with Max.
他在伦敦吗
He's in London?
对  去处理文件了
Yeah. Taking care of some paperwork.
他让我给这里加把锁  我差点把你锁在里面
He asked me to put a padlock on here. I nearly locked you in.
真可惜
It's a shame.
这里要荒废了
This place going to ruin.
现在没船了
Well... no boat now.
迈克斯不喜欢驾船出海
Max doesn't like to sail.
贝恩说她是淹死的
Ben said she drowned.
抱歉  我以为你知道
I'm sorry. I assumed you knew.
-我不知道  -那天天气很差
- No. - Ah, it's... It was brutal weather.
即便对她这个好驾船人来说
Even for her. She was an excellent sailor.
船沉了
The boat went down.
一直没找到
They never recovered it.
两个月后她被冲上了埃奇库姆的岸边
She washed up in Edgcumbe some... two months later.
两个月  天呐
Two months? My God!
可怜的迈克西姆
Poor Maxim.
是我载他去认了尸体
Drove him down there myself to identify the body.
你不必为过去所扰
You know, you really mustn't dwell on the past.
你们很般配  他已经走出来了
You're so good for Max. He's a changed man.
她当时一定很害怕
She must have been so afraid.
一个人在海上
Out there alone.
她什么都不怕
She wasn't afraid of anything.
我能问你点事吗  弗兰克  跟我说实话
Can I ask you something, Frank? And promise to tell me the truth.
这不公平  我还不知道你要问什么呢
Hardly fair, isn't it. Don't know what you're gonna ask me.
吕蓓卡很美吗
Was Rebecca very beautiful?
是的
Yes.
我想她是...
Yes, I suppose she was...
我这辈子见过的最美的人
the most beautiful creature I ever saw in my life.
吕
这裙子的确很美  不是吗
It is beautiful, isn't it?
我把它照原样放着
I keep it just the way it was.
就好像她只是出去一会儿
It's as if she'd just gone out for a while.
你吓了我一跳
You startled me.
这件是她的最爱
This was her favorite.
那晚我替她摆在床上
I laid it out for her that night.
来  拿着
Go on, hold it.
摸摸看
Touch it.
她不要贴身女仆
She wouldn't have a lady's maid, you know.
她说  "丹尼  我除了你谁也不要"
"I don't want anyone but you, Danny."
你看到她有多高了吗
Do you see how tall she was?
以她的身材穿什么都很好看
Hmm. She could wear anything with a figure like hers.
每晚我都会替她梳头发
I'd brush her hair for her every evening.
她会说  "快来  丹尼  帮我梳头发"
"Come on, Danny, hair drill." she'd say.
我会站在她身后
I'd stand behind her
每次为她梳上20分钟
and brush away for 20 minutes at a time.
她有一头浓密的深色秀发
That great mass of dark hair.
他会加入
He joined in.
他很喜欢为她这样做
He loved to do that for her.
他们会为晚宴打扮  客人们都在楼下等着
They'd be dressing for dinner, guests waiting downstairs.
"再用力点  迈克斯  再用力点"
"Harder, Max, harder!"
他就会放声大笑
And he'd roar with laughter.
那时他总是开怀大笑
He was always laughing back then.
他会帮你梳头发吗
Does he brush your hair?
不会
No.
丹弗斯太太
Mrs. Danvers,
是老爷叫你把房间维持原样的吗
does Mr. de Winter ask you to keep the room like this?
他不必说出口
He doesn't have to.
她还在这里
She's still here.
你能感觉到她吗
Can you feel her?
我很好奇她怎么看你
I wonder what she's thinking about you.
抢走她的丈夫  用着她的名字
Taking her husband and... using her name.
-她肯定希望他快乐  -快乐
- I'm sure she'd want him to be happy. - Happy?
不  他永远不会再快乐了
No, he'll never be happy.
她是他的一生挚爱
She was the love of his life.
迈克西姆
Maxim?
早上好  夫人
Good morning, madam.
天呐  你抓伤了自己
Oh, dear! You've been scratchin'.
想我了吗
Have we missed ya?
你好  想必你是新的德温特夫人了
Hello! You must be the new Mrs. de Winter.
我想你弄错了
Uh, I think there's been a mistake.
-德温特先生在伦敦  -他把你一个人留在这儿吗
- Mr. de Winter's in London. - He's left you on your own?
他不怕有无赖来把你抢走吗
Isn't he afraid some bounder might come and carry you off?
我是杰克·费弗尔  你好
I'm Jack Favell. How do you do?
你想把名片留下吗
Well, did you want to leave your card?
而且如此礼貌  都不好意思直接叫我滚
And too polite to tell me to bugger off.
你真是个甜心
You are a sweetheart.
不用担心  我只是过来看看丹尼
Not to worry. I just popped by to see Danny.
她邀请我来喝茶
She's invited me for tea.
-但我到得太早了  -丹弗斯太太吗
- I'm horribly early, though. - Mrs. Danvers?
所以我想着先在附近转转
That's why I thought I'd better hover around out here,
否则我可能会被她打手腕
otherwise I might get a smack on the wrist.
费弗尔先生  你去哪里
Mr. Favell? Where are you going?
查理  过来
Charlie, come on.
-等等  费弗尔先生  -来了  先生
- Excuse me, Mr. Favell! - Coming, sir.
-菲利帕  -进来  查理
- Phillippa! - Come on in, Charlie.
吁  吁  吁  别激动
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Stand down.
-放松  星光  -冷静
- Easy, Starlight, easy. - Steady.
你精力太旺盛了  他们一直忽视你
You've got too much energy. They've been neglecting you.
我不感到意外
That's not a surprise.
只有吕蓓卡能治住你  不是吗
Rebecca was the only one who could handle you, wasn't she, old boy?
是的
Yes.
你认识吕蓓卡吗
You knew Rebecca?
她是我表妹
She's my cousin. Was.
好了
That's it.
我们拉匹马出去转转吧
Let's take one of the horses out for a turn.
不了  我不会骑马
Oh, no. I really... I don't know how.
我可以教你  难道你有更好的安排吗
Well, I can teach you. Or have you something better to be doing?
-我该怎么...  -我数到三  把腿跨过去
- How do I... - On three, swing your leg over.
-准备好了吗  -你是要...
- Ready? - Do you...
一  二  三
One, two, three.
能帮我蹬一下吗  好了
Can you give me a stirrup? All right.
你是要...
Are you...
我们不会骑得太快的
We won't go too fast.
就是这样
That's it.
你感觉怎么样
How do you feel?
-好了  现在你拿着缰绳  -好的
- Right, now you take the reins. - Oh, all right.
-轻轻拉着  -好的
- Be nice and loose. - Yeah.
放低一点  对了
And low. That's it.
-明白了  -放在你的大腿上
- Got it. - Right here on your lap.
切记  要把腿夹紧
Now, very important. Squeeze the thighs.
让马知道你在它背上
Let the beast know you're there.
你今晚可能会全身酸痛
You're gonna be wickedly sore this evening.
现在跟着我一起动  准备好了吗
Now just move with me. Ready?
好的
All right.
亲爱的  我能问你点事吗
Darling, may I ask you something?
迈克斯跟你说过那次事故吗
Has Max ever talked to you about the accident?
他没提过吕蓓卡那天去过伦敦吗
And he never mentioned Rebecca's trip to London that day?
没有
No.
他对这件事只字不提
No, he won't speak of it at all.
这么说你不知道他有没有见过她
So, you don't know if he saw her
就在她那晚回来
when she got back that night,
准备出海之前
before she took the boat out?
不知道
No.
她想告诉我一些事
There's something she wanted to tell me.
很重要的事
Something very important.
不知道到底是什么事...
And not knowing what it was...
真的让我难以承受
That's really been a hard thing.
我破坏了自己玩世不恭的形象  对吗
I'm not doing my roguish image any good, am I?
你应该再来一次  问问迈克西姆
You should come back and ask Maxim.
我会的
Well, I would.
但其实我被禁止来这里
But I'm afraid I'm a little bit banned from visiting.
实际上  你最好不要提我今天来过
In fact, it's best if you don't mention my being here at all today.
我还以为你们是朋友
I... I thought you were friends.
算不上
Not really, no.
我不希望我们俩中的任何一个
And I would hate for either one of us
经受到他有名的暴脾气
to be on the receiving end of that famous temper of his.
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
你们还没在一起生活多久
Well, it is still early days.
我最好别让丹尼等了  你知道她是什么样的
Well, I better not keep Danny waiting. You know how she is.
你为什么邀请了他
Why did you invite him?
杰克·费弗尔
Jack Favell.
你邀请他来喝茶
You asked him for tea,
你明知道老爷不准他来
knowing full well Mr. de Winter has banned him from the property.
你一定是弄错了  夫人
There must be some mistake, madam.
我已经有一年多没见过费弗尔先生了
I haven't seen Mr. Favell for over a year.
你好  弗里思
Hello, Frith.
你好  老爷  费弗尔先生不请自来过
Hello, sir. Mr. Favell has made an unannounced visit.
我不管她对弗里思说了什么
I don't care what she told Frith!
费弗尔先生跟我说是她邀请他来这儿的
Mr. Favell told me that she invited him here.
难道是丹弗斯太太逼你
Well, Mrs. Danvers, I suppose she forced you
和他一起骑马的吗
to go riding with him, did she?
不  我可以解释
No, I can explain!
-解释什么  -我本来打算告诉你的  真的
- Explain what? - I was going to tell you, I was.
想告诉我你是怎么把他拉到船库里的
Want to tell me how you dragged him down to the boathouse?
怎么跟他展示你漂亮的新睡衣吗
Parade your fancy new night clothes for him?
你怎么能这么想
How could you even think that?
如果我知道你会生气
I'd never have let him on the property
我绝不会让他进入庄园  迈克西姆
if I'd known it would upset you, Maxim.
拜托  我爱你
Please. I love you.
真的吗
Oh, do you?
是丹弗斯太太邀请他过来的
Mrs. Danvers invited him here.
我不想再听到你说丹弗斯了
I don't wanna hear another word about Danvers!
请进
Come in.
丹弗斯太太
Mrs. Danvers.
我是来辞退你的
I've come to give you your notice.
老爷同意了吗
Has Mr. de Winter agreed to this?
这是我的决定
The decision is mine.
其实
You see...
我从吕蓓卡小时候就开始照顾她了
I looked after Rebecca when she was a little girl.
她结婚之后  我们一起来到了这里
We came here together when she was first married.
我是她的朋友
I was her friend.
是可以分享她秘密的人
Someone to share her secrets.
这种关系是无法打破的
Bond like that can't be broke.
也无法取代  我不该期望和您建立这种关系
Can't be replaced. I was wrong to expect that from you.
你会找到另一个庄园
Well, you'll find another house.
不
No.
我们女人
We women,
要么结婚  要么去当仆人
we can either marry or go into service,
我太老了  这两种选择都不合适
and I'm too old for either.
我们会确保你衣食无忧
Well, we'll make sure that you're provided for.
这和钱无关  只是...
Oh, it's not about money. It's...
这对我来说不是工作  吕蓓卡是我的人生
This wasn't a job for me. Rebecca was my life.
是的
Yes.
如果我让您失望了  我很抱歉
I'm sorry if I failed you.
这不是我的本意
I didn't mean to let you down.
只是您看上去一心想要我行我素
It was just you seemed so set on doing things your own way.
不  这一切对我来说都很陌生
No. This is all very new to me.
这个庄园  还有佣人...
The house, the staff...
我只是...
I just...
我觉得德温特先生也希望你能帮我
I think that Mr. de Winter hoped that you'd help me.
您并没有向我寻求帮助
You didn't ask for my help.
那么
Well...
如果我现在请求你的帮助呢
what if I asked for it now?
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我是个蠢货
I was an idiot.
那不是你的错
It's not your fault.
我知道不是
I know it wasn't.
我真的很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
曼陀丽舞会
好吧
Okay.
开胃菜  牡蛎
很好  夫人  我马上去印出来
Very good, madam. Perfect. I'll have them printed at once.
如果您希望伦敦的沃斯店定制您的服装
Oh, and we must let Voce in London know before Friday
我们必须在周五之前通知他们
if you wish them to make your costume.
好的  恐怕我还没有做好决定
Yes. I'm afraid I'm drawing a bit of a blank there.
您是舞会上最重要的女士
Well, you'll be the most important lady at the ball.
-选择服装的时候请谨记这一点  -好的
- So, choose something with that in mind. - Yes.
自信点
Oh, be confident.
让他们看看您的自然美
Let them see your natural beauty.
夫人
Madam?
如果我这么说不会太冒昧的话...
If it's not too forward of me...
丹弗斯太太说  您还没有决定要穿什么
Mrs. Danvers said you'd not picked out what to wear yet, and...
不知道您想不想听听我的建议
I wondered if you'd want an idea.
好的  当然  什么建议都可以  坐吧
Yes, please, anything. Sit down.
画廊里的那些旧画作
Just... the old paintings in the gallery.
我一直认为画里的服装会是最漂亮的舞会礼服
I always thought they'd make the most beautiful costume.
特别是身穿红裙的那位女士
Especially the lady in the red dress.
很明智的选择
Brilliant choice.
克拉丽斯和我说了
Clarice informed me.
请容许我说  这件裙子配得上庄园的女主人
And if I may say so, one worthy of the lady of this house.
我道歉
I do apologize.
公爵和公爵夫人
礼炮烟花
好的  把这个拿给丹弗斯太太好吗
Right. Will you take this down to Mrs. Danvers?
-确保她把一切准备妥当  -好的
- Make sure she has everything. - Right.
-多谢  -如果你们一直走到大宅...
- Thank you very much. - And if you go through to the house...
-抱歉  -我很抱歉
- Oh, sorry. - I'm sorry!
-欢迎  欢迎  -你还好吗
- Welcome. Welcome. - Are you quite all right?
-是的  现在有点风  弗兰克  -是的
- Yes. There's bit of a wind, Frank. - Well, yes.
-希望不会下雨  -肯定不会的
- Hope it doesn't rain. - It'll come to nothing, I'm sure.
天呐
Oh, dear.
沃斯
-什么  快放手  不许看  -我不能看看吗
- What? Hands off! Don't! - Can't I just see?
不不不  你会毁了惊喜的
No, no, no, no, no, you'll ruin the surprise.
你知道我不喜欢惊喜
You know I don't like surprises.
你肯定会喜欢这个惊喜
Well, you'll like this one.
你会认不出我的
You won't recognize me.
我真为你自豪
I'm so proud of you.
别让我一个人在下面等太久
Now, don't you leave me down there too long.
那就快出去吧  这样我才能准备
Then get out so I can get ready.
给
Here you go.
不  我不能喝
No, I couldn't.
别犯傻了  没事的  我不会告诉别人
Don't be silly. It's all right, I won't tell anyone.
不行  走开  你不能进来
No, no, no, no, go away! You can't come in!
夫人  客人们到了
The guests are arriving, ma'am.
好吧  我们去欢迎一下
Oh, all right. Let's greet them.
请告知他们  夫人马上就下去
Please inform them madam will be down presently.
很好
Very good.
-你一个人躲在这里干什么  -没什么
- What are you doing lurking over here? - Nothing.
-这就像以前一样  不是吗  -挺好的
- It's just like old times, isn't it? - Mmm, it's good.
你的服装呢
Where's your outfit?
-这就是我的服装  贾尔斯  -很棒
- This is my outfit, Giles. - It's marvelous.
真热闹  香槟啊
Palaver! Oh, champagne.
-和往常一样迟到了  -你这次是什么理由
- Late as usual. - So, what's your excuse?
有棵树倒下来挡着车道了  得把树移走
Tree down across the drive. Had to get it moved.
不  我是说这身衣服
No, no, for this.
但我每年都穿这身衣服  好吗
But I wear it every year, mate.
好了  她终于来了
All right. Finally. Hey, here she comes.
德温特先生  你好吗
How do you do, Mr. de Winter?
这是在戏弄我吗
Is this some kind of joke?
当然不是  是照着那幅画  我想着...
Of course not. It's the painting. I thought...
去换衣服
Go and change.
怎么了  我做错...
What is it? What have I...
现在就去换衣服
Go and change now.
我不明白
I don't understand.
-我做错了什么  -我叫你现在就去
- What have I done wrong? - I said now!
很抱歉  夫人  我不知道会这样
I'm sorry. Please, madam, I never knew.
这是丹弗斯太太的主意
It was Mrs. Danvers' idea.
吕蓓卡以前穿过这件裙子  对吗
Rebecca wore this before, didn't she?
丹弗斯太太说他肯定会很开心...
Mrs. Danvers said he'd be so pleased and
你也会很开心
you'd be so pleased.
拿着
Hold that.
-真是太糟糕了  -叫人毛骨悚然  不是吗
- That's most unfortunate. - It was uncanny, wasn't it?
-不  我做不到  -胡说  亲爱的  你必须这么做
- No, I can't. - Oh, bosh! Darling, you have to.
不
No.
事情没有那么糟
It's not as bad as all that.
你不明白  我做不到
You don't understand, I can't.
都这样了  我还怎么下楼
Not after this. Not after what I've done.
你怎么会想得到
How were you to know?
去洗洗脸
Now, wash your face,
我去帮你找衣服穿  好吗
and I'll find you something to wear, all right?
我应该想到的
I should've known.
-我就不该穿这件裙子  -振作点
- I should never have worn it. - Pull yourself together.
你可以坐在这里自责一整晚
You can sit up here all night feeling sorry for yourself,
或者可以和我一起下楼
or you can come downstairs with me
一笑置之  怎么样
and have a good old laugh about it, hmm?
他的表情...
His face...
他绝不会这么对她说话
He wouldn't have spoken like that to her.
你们是迥然不同的人
You're very different people,
这没什么好羞耻的
and that's nothing to be ashamed of.
-好的  -来
- Okay. - Come on.
你现在不在欧洲了  沉着点
You're not on the continent now. Let's have a stiff upper lip.
-怎么样  -好的
- What? - Oh, yes.
这件应该可以
This'll do.
我会没事的
I'll be all right.
你做得很好
Good show.
-楼下见  -好的
- I'll see you downstairs. - Yes.
-好吗  -好的
- Yes? - Yes.
没有什么能让我感到高兴...
Nothing would make me happy...
克罗恩勋爵  克罗恩夫人  这位是德温特夫人
Lord Crowan, Lady Crowan, may I present Mrs. de Winter.
真可惜  没能看见你穿礼裙的样子
Oh, rotten luck about your frock not turning up.
-是啊  -没关系  你看上去很漂亮
- Yes. - Oh, never mind. You look lovely,
而且比我这身滑稽的服装要舒服多了
and far more comfortable than I am in this ridiculous getup.
别犯傻了  亲爱的  你看上去美极了
Oh, don't be silly, darling. You look divine.
-迈克西姆  我...  -这主意就是个错误
- Maxim, I... - This whole idea was a mistake.
我就不该带你回来
I should never have brought you back here.
士兵和水手从战场上回来了
There are sailors and soldiers returned from the war.
小姐  这里不是你待的地方
This ain't no place for you, miss.
他们勇敢地为祖国而战
Who bravely have fought in their country's cause.
结果回到家却饥肠辘辘
To come home, to be starved,
还是待在以前的地方更好...
best stayed where they was...
吕蓓卡  吕蓓卡  吕蓓卡  吕蓓卡
Rebecca! Rebecca! Rebecca! Rebecca!
吕蓓卡  吕蓓卡
Rebecca! Rebecca!
迈克西姆
Maxim?
好了  现在你明白了吗
There, do you see now?
你永远无法取代她
You'll never replace her.
-你无法取代她  -是你干的
- You can't replace her. - You did this.
-你从一开始就针对我  -不
- You've been against me from the start. - No.
-我是在帮你  -你骗了我  你策划了一切
- I was helping you. - You tricked me. You planned this.
你和我都清楚  你什么也不是
You and I both know you are nothing.
你一文不值
You're worthless.
你配不上他  配不上这栋大宅
Not worthy of him and not worthy of this house.
他绝不会爱你
He'll never love you.
他为什么要爱你呢
And why should he?
他爱过
He did.
不  他无法爱上你  因为你不是她
No, he can't love you because you're not her.
你真该见见她
You should've seen her.
在16岁时  她骑着父亲的马  那马野得很
At 16 years old, on her father's horse, a huge brute,
但她驯服了它
but she mastered him.
等她调教完马后
By the time she finished with him,
它已经顺服得像羊羔一般
he was nothing but froth and blood.
我让她失望了  由得你在这里住了这么久
I've let her down, allowing you here for so long.
她无法容忍的
She won't stand for it.
"我们地狱见  丹尼  我们地狱见"
"I'll see you in hell, Danny! I'll see you in hell first!"
但吕蓓卡死了  她已经死了
But Rebecca's dead! She's dead!
他会离开你  他会和你离婚
He'll leave you, he'll divorce you.
然后你要怎么办
And then what'll you do?
我走就是了
I'll just go.
走  你要去哪儿
You'll go? Go where?
你现在没法再婚了
You can't remarry now.
你肯定也没法管理一栋宅子
You certainly can't look after a house.
你没有家庭支持你
You don't have any family to support you.
没关系
It's all right.
我知道你的感受  其实没那么糟
I know how you feel. It's not as bad as all that.
很快就会结束
It'll be very quick.
别害怕  这是为了大家好
Don't be scared. It's all for the best.
没人希望你在这里
No one wants you here.
弗里思  罗伯特  快来
Frith! Robert! Come quickly.
一艘拖网渔船搁浅了  叫海岸警卫队来
A trawler's run aground. Get the coast guard.
-他们正赶来  老爷  -迈克西姆
- They're on the way, sir. - Maxim.
他在那里干什么
What's he doin' down there?
丹尼尔  等我
Daniel, wait for me.
快点  用点力  就这样
Move on, now. Get up, now. That's it.
后退  让一让
Stand back! Coming forward!
潜水员下海了
Diver's down there.
肯定是要捞值钱的东西
Must've been something valuable.
是为了那艘拖网渔船
That's for the trawler.
他们还发现了别的东西
They found somethin' else down there.
就这样  好样的
That's it! Good lad!
"我归来"号
我什么都没说  对吧
I never said nothing. Did I?
她现在不会回来了
She'll not come back now.
鱼肯定已经把她啃食完了  对吧
The fishes will have devoured her by now, ain't they?
弗兰克
Frank.
你不该来这里
You really shouldn't be here.
别在那等了  快点  都走吧  后退
Don't wait there. Come on. Everybody move. Stand back.
她的船里有一具尸体  跟她的发色相同
The body was found in her boat. The same color hair.
还有她结婚戒指上的镌刻
And the engravings on her wedding ring.
毫无疑问就是她
There's no doubt it's her.
别说傻话了
Don't be an imbecile.
我想这其中肯定有个合理的解释  对吧
I'm sure there's a perfectly logical explanation, hmm?
你不觉得这很奇怪吗
You don't think it's odd?
你弟弟认领
That your brother identified
并埋葬了陌生人的尸体  当作自己的妻子
and buried the body of a stranger as his wife?
不  贾尔斯  我不觉得奇怪
No, Giles, I don't.
如果你那么关心  怎么不自己去问迈克西姆呢
If you're so concerned, why don't you go and ask Maxim yourself.
我倒是想  但已经好几小时没人看见他了
I would, but no one's seen him for hours. I mean...
怎么回事  为什么警察在询问他
What's happened? Why were the police questioning him?
不  他没回过家  他们什么时候放了他
No. He's not been home. Why? When did they release him?
拜托  你见到他后务必联系我
...please, do let me know when you see him.
没问题  弗兰克  谢谢
Yes, of course, Frank. Thank you.
别担心  好好照顾自己
Don't worry. Take care of yourself.
都结束了  她赢了
It's over. She's won.
谁赢了
Who's won?
吕蓓卡
Rebecca.
如果他们找到的是她的尸体
If that's her body they found,
那你之前埋葬的人是谁
who is it you buried?
我不知道
I don't know.
迈克西姆
Maxim.
告诉我真相
The truth.
我不知道  我发誓
I don't know. I swear it.
她怎么淹死的
How did she drown?
她没有
She didn't.
别骗我
Don't lie to me.
她没有淹死
She didn't drown.
她那时已经死了
She was already dead.
她的船被动了手脚
Her boat was damaged.
是我干的
I damaged it.
我故意的
Deliberately.
迈克西姆
Oh, Maxim.
你不了解她
You didn't know her.
没人了解
Nobody did.
她在我们度蜜月时告诉我今后的生活会如何
She told me on our honeymoon how it would be.
她会保留她在伦敦的公寓
How she would keep her flat in London.
和一个又一个男人鬼混  连她的表哥也不放过
Her parade of men. Even her own cousin.
拜托  迈克西姆
Please, Maxim!
她很享受这样  扮演这个角色
She relished it. Playing the part.
所谓的完美妻子  她知道我绝不会和她离婚
The perfect wife, knowing that I would never divorce her.
因为你爱她
'Cause you loved her.
我恨她
I hated her.
恨她的残酷
Hated her cruelty.
恨我的懦弱
I hated my cowardice.
我知道自己不会和她离婚
Knowing that I wouldn't divorce her.
我知道自己绝不能玷污家名
Knowing I could never do that to our name.
她是怎么死的
How did she die?
她从伦敦回来后
When she came back from London,
说正等着费弗尔来
she told me she was expecting a visit from Favell.
我到这里时  就她一个人在
When I got here, she was alone.
她看起来不同寻常  脸色苍白
She looked different. She was pale.
她去伦敦看医生了
She'd seen a doctor in London.
她说  "假设我怀了孩子  迈克斯
She said, "Imagine if I had a child, Max.
你永远无法证明那不是你的骨肉"
You could never prove it wasn't yours."
她夺走了我的尊严还不够
See, it wasn't enough for her to take my pride.
她还想夺走我的名字  我的家  我的一切
She wanted to take my name, my home, everything.
然后她说  "来啊  迈克斯  动手吧"
And she said, "Go on, Max, do it."
"你只需要扣下扳机  之后你就自由了"
"All you have to do is pull the trigger and you'll be free."
求你了
Please.
子弹径直穿过了她的身体
Bullet went straight through her.
但她没有马上倒下  只是站在原地
She didn't fall right away. She just stood there.
无比平静
So calm.
像释怀了一般
Almost relieved.
然后她就死了
And then she was gone.
一直以来我以为你还爱着吕蓓卡
All this time I thought you still loved Rebecca.
你为什么不告诉我
Why didn't you tell me?
我说不出口
I couldn't.
我太害怕会失去你
I was so afraid I'd have lost you.
去报警吧  告诉他们一切
Go to the police, tell them everything.
你什么都不知道  你不会受牵连
You didn't know. Nothing'll happen to you.
如果你不想再和我扯上关系  我也能理解
I understand if you want nothing more to do with me.
那是你的选择
That's your choice.
你弄错了
You made a mistake...
认错了尸体
identifying the body.
那都是因为你太悲痛受创
It was the grief, the trauma.
除了我们没人知道真相  其他人永远不会知道
Nobody knows but us. Nobody will ever know.
她没有赢  迈克西姆
No, she hasn't won, Maxim.
她没有赢
She hasn't won.
我们不会让她赢
We won't let her.
你不用和他们说什么
You don't have to speak to them.
全体起立  尊敬的詹姆斯·克劳奇先生来了
All stand for the Right Honorable James Crouch.
后退
Stand back.
肃静  大家安静
Order! Settle down.
这是...  坐下  先生
This is the... Sit down, sir.
本次审理是为调查
This is the coroner's inquest
吕蓓卡·德温特的死因
into the discovery of the body of Rebecca de Winter.
此案目前不是刑事诉讼
This is not currently a criminal proceeding.
我们只是来查明德温特夫人是怎么死的
We are here only to ascertain how Mrs. de Winter died.
本庭现在听取
The court will now hear
克里斯警局韦尔奇警长的证词
from Detective Welch of the Kerrith police.
韦尔奇警长
Detective Welch.
德温特先生去年指认的那具尸体...
The body Mr. de Winter identified last year...
并不是他妻子的
was not his wife.
事实上  吕蓓卡·德温特的尸体
In fact, Rebecca de Winter's body
是从她的船舱里打捞到的
was recovered from the cabin of her boat.
这让我很困惑
That troubled me.
同样令人困惑的还有船的破损情况
As did the nature of the damage to the vessel.
情况如何
And what was that nature?
我们发现吃水线下方有四个洞
We found four holes below the waterline
形状和用鱼叉凿出的洞一致
consistent with those made by a ship's gaff.
-或用长钉  -说明什么
- Or spike. - Suggesting what?
说明船是被蓄意凿洞弄沉的
That the boat was deliberately scuttled.
死因裁判官大人  在我看来
In my opinion, Mr. Coroner,
此次审理只能作出两种裁决  非此即彼
this inquest can return one of only two verdicts.
此案不是自杀就是他杀
Suicide or unlawful killing.
你夫人去世那天去过伦敦
Your wife made a trip to London the day she died.
到时间了
It's time.
你在警方录的口供中说
In your statement to the police, you say your wife seemed
你夫人回来后似乎"心事重重  郁郁寡欢"
"Preoccupied and unhappy" when she returned.
别表现得太防备  回答问题时保持镇静
Don't be defensive. Answer their questions calmly.
她去伦敦做什么
What was the purpose of her trip?
不知道
No idea.
这正常吗
Was it normal for your wife
你妻子不和自己丈夫商量这种事
not to discuss such matters with her husband?
你是在暗示我的婚姻有问题吗
Are you implying there were problems in my marriage?
我只是想弄清楚为什么去年
I'm trying to understand how you apparently failed
你并没认出尸体不是你妻子的
to recognize your own wife last year.
她那时已在海上漂了两个月
She'd been two months at sea.
她漂流了20英里
She drifted 20 miles.
尸体已经泡肿腐烂
She was bloated, decomposing,
她的胳膊没了  面容尽毁
her arms ripped off, ` and there was nothing left of her face.
肃静  肃静
Order! Order!
我刚刚真是愚蠢又傲慢
I was arrogant and stupid.
-我慌了  -不  你只是很激动
- I lost my nerve. - No, you were passionate.
他们会相信你的
They'll believe it.
还有谁知道她去伦敦见了医生
Who else knows she saw a doctor in London?
你  我  还有那位医生
You, me, and the doctor.
他们不可能找到任何物证的
They're not likely to find any physical evidence.
毕竟尸体在海上漂了那么久
Not after so long at sea.
那位医生是他们仅有的证据
The doctor is all they have.
我和费弗尔先生说了这不欢迎他  但他非要来
I did tell Mr. Favell he wasn't welcome, but he insisted.
谢谢  丹弗斯太太
Thank you, Mrs. Danvers.
你到底想要什么
What the hell do you want?
再来一杯威士忌苏打就挺好
Another whiskey and soda would be nice.
事关吕蓓卡
It's about Rebecca,
所以你要不要先叫你妻子去睡觉
so you might want to send your wife off to bed.
我哪儿都不去
I'm not going anywhere.
你和吕蓓卡间的事我全都知道
I know all about you and Rebecca.
是吗
Really?
你全都知道  是吗
You know all about that, do you?
你差点被我抓到  费弗尔
You were close, Favell.
如果那天晚上我抓到了你俩在一起...
If I'd caught you here that night with her...
那天晚上他根本没来过
He was never here that night.
但是她确实邀请了我
But she did invite me.
这是关键
And that's the point.
不是自杀就是谋杀
Suicide or foul play,
那家伙是这么说的  对吗
that's what the chap said, wasn't it?
约别人见面...
Now, inviting someone over...
听起来不像是一个准备自杀的人
doesn't really sound like the sort of thing one would do
会做的事  对吗
if one was planning to end it all, does it?
过去这一年  这事一直折磨着我
And that's what's been driving me mad this last year.
不过真相开始浮出水面
But it's beginning to make sense.
她终于决定要离开你
She finally decided to leave you.
所以你就把她杀了  对吗
Is that why you killed her?
你没有证据
You've no proof.
只是你和我各执一词
It's your word against mine.
不
No.
是你和吕蓓卡各执一词
It's your word against Rebecca's.
"收到此信后来曼陀丽庄园
"Come to Manders when you get this.
有事相告
I've something to tell you
盼尽快与你相见  吕蓓卡上"
and I want to see you as soon as possible. Rebecca."
让我看看
Let me see.
-滚出我的房子  -别被他激怒  迈克西姆
- Get out of my house. - Don't rise to it, Maxim.
没错  别被我激怒了  迈克斯
Yes. Don't rise to it, Max.
其实我只是来感谢你的
I only came by to thank you, really.
这些年来  你一直都很慷慨
You've been so generous over the years,
和我们这么多男人分享你的妻子
sharing your wife with so many of us chaps.
事实上  我还想要不要试试勾搭你的新夫人
Actually, I wondered if I might try my luck with the new one.
来了  这就是我跟你说的暴脾气
There it is. There's that temper I told you about.
你要多少钱
How much do you want?
她比看起来要聪明  对吗
She's cleverer than she looks, this one, isn't she?
好像流血了
Seems to be a spot of blood.
天呐
Dearie me.
不过她说得对
She's right, though.
我不是有钱人  迈克斯
I'm not a rich man, Max.
我太沉迷赌博  不可能有钱
Well, I'm too fond of gambling for that,
但我确实喜欢上了某种生活方式
but I do have a certain lifestyle that I've come to enjoy.
我想大概一万英镑
I imagine I could get by on around...
能换我这张便条
£10,000 for the note
并且换我明天出庭作证时不提此事
and my silence when I take the stand tomorrow.
你这是敲诈
This is blackmail.
-你要干什么  -报警
- What are you doing? - Calling the police.
好  报警啊
Yeah. Call the police.
我们也许还能被关在同一间牢房
Might even put us in the same cell.
不过关不了多久
Not for long, though.
你应该会被绞刑处死  迈克西姆
I imagine you're looking at the noose, Maxim.
应韦尔奇警长的要求
At Inspector Welch's request,
今早的庭审有所变动
there's a change to this morning's proceedings.
我们现在听取
We shall now hear
曼陀丽庄园的管家丹弗斯太太的证词
from the de Winters' housekeeper, Mrs. Danvers.
可以说  曼陀丽内没什么事是你不知道的
Safe to say not much occurs at Manderley
或未经你准许的  我说得对吗
without your knowledge or say-so, would I be right?
我负责确保庄园的有序运转
I ensure the smooth running of the house.
因此你才会发现
Which is how you came to be aware
已故德温特夫人和费弗尔先生之间的关系
of the late Mrs. de Winter's relationship with Mr. Favell.
我知道他们很亲密
Well, I was aware they were, intimate.
但是我家夫人的私生活是她的私事
But my lady's private affairs were her own.
理应如此
So they should be.
不过因为案情十分反常
But since these circumstances are far from normal,
或许你能当庭分享下你昨晚和我说的事
perhaps you'd share with the court what you told me last night.
我得知有一张给费弗尔先生的便条
I learned of a note addressed to Mr. Favell.
我力劝他给你看那张便条
I urged him to share that note with you.
德温特先生似乎很不想让法庭发现那张便条
A note Mr. de Winter seemed keen to keep from this court.
是的
Yes.
便条的内容是邀请费弗尔先生
The note was inviting Mr. Favell
在德温特夫人去世的那天晚上
to join Mrs. de Winter at the house...
去庄园见她
the night my lady died.
德温特先生想用钱交换那张便条
Mr. de Winter offered money in exchange for that note.
便条是吕蓓卡·德温特写的
The note was from Rebecca de Winter.
是的
It was.
她写了有急事要告诉他
She wrote she had urgent news to share with him.
费弗尔先生收到的开价是多少钱
And how much was Mr. Favell offered?
一万镑
£10,000.
这张支票
A check...
是德温特先生开的
written by Mr. de Winter...
用来换取那张便条
in exchange for the note.
你凭什么这么说  仅凭一张支票
Where does it say that? All you have is a check.
-说明不了用途  -肃静  女士  肃静
- Nothing to say what it's for. - Order! Madam, order.
丹弗斯太太  你认为
Mrs. Danvers, do you think it's likely
吕蓓卡·德温特有否可能是溺水自杀
Rebecca de Winter drowned herself?
不  先生  我不这么认为
No, sir. I do not.
在她去世前的几周里
In the weeks, leading up to her death,
她变得倦怠乏力
she had become fatigued
总是感觉恶心想吐
and was feeling sick.
她让我放宽了她的裤子腰带
And she asked me to let out the waistband in her trousers.
她的肚子变大了
Her belly was growing.
德温特夫人去世那天去了趟伦敦
Mrs. de Winter went to London the day she died.
她有没有说原因
Did she say why?
-没有  -奇怪
- No. - Odd.
一定是非常私人的事情
It must've been something deeply personal
她不想让我知道
for her to have kept that from me.
比如说  见她的医生
Like, say, an appointment with her doctor.
并不是你们料想的家庭医生
Not her family doctor, as you might expect,
而是某个低调谨慎的医生
but someone discreet.
她躲避窥探
Away from prying eyes
似乎并不想
as if news of her condition
让别人知道她的身体状况
was something she wished to keep private.
她只愿意告诉她的情人
A wish to share only with her lover,
杰克·费弗尔
Jack Favell.
你这该死的杀人犯  你是该死的杀人犯
You murdering bastard. You're a murdering bastard!
你还杀了我的孩子  我希望他们把你绞死
With my child! I hope they hang you.
我希望他们把你绞死  你杀了吕蓓卡
I hope they hang you! You murdered Rebecca!
结论只可能有两种
Only two possible verdicts.
希望你赞同  先生  本案完全没有自杀动机
I hope you agree, sir, that there's no motive at all for suicide.
但显然有谋杀动机
But a clear one for murder.
审理暂缓  等待刑事调查结果
This inquest is suspended pending a criminal investigation.
女士们先生们  我宣布休庭
Ladies and gentlemen, court is adjourned.
没人能凌驾于法律之上
Nobody's above the law.
放开我  放开
Get your hands off me! Get off!
丹弗斯太太
Mrs. Danvers.
什么也没别说  他们没有任何证据
Say nothing. They can't prove anything.
我要她的日程簿  日记  通讯录
I want her appointment books, diaries, address books,
家庭账本  所有东西
household finances, everything.
她在某个时间见过那医生  并付了他钱
She saw that doctor sometime and she paid him.
罗  开始打电话询问伦敦的妇科医生
Roe, start placing calls to women specialists in London.
不  不
No. No.
抱歉  请问你们有搜查许可吗
I'm sorry, do you have permission to search this place?
吕
德温特夫人
Mrs. de Winter?
-弗兰克  -怎么了
- Frank! - What?
我需要她的支票  银行对账单
I need her checks, her bank statements.
任何写有她医生的姓名和地址的东西
Anything that has the name and address of her doctor.
好  是这些
Right. Here it is.
我知道你需要什么
I know what you need.
-我需要找到医生  -你要找她的医生  这里
- I need a doctor. - You need her doctor? There.
约·贝克医生合伙诊所
一定就是这个
That must be it.
你真无耻
Shame on you.
太无耻了  你竟然站在他那边
Shame on you for taking his side.
我没站在任何人那边  丹弗斯太太  我...
I'm not taking anyone's side, Mrs. Danvers. I...
还有你  弗兰克
And you, Frank.
白天舔着德温特夫人的靴子
Licking Mr. de Winter's boots by day,
晚上抓挠小屋的门
and pawing at the cottage door at night.
像个小男孩一样啜泣
Sobbing like a schoolboy.
她看不起你们所有人
She despised you all.
伦敦的那些男人  参加曼陀丽舞会的那些男人
The men in London, the men at the Manderley parties.
你们都只是她的玩物
You were nothing but playthings for her.
女人为什么不能找乐子
And why shouldn't a woman amuse herself?
她随心所欲地生活  我的吕蓓卡
She lived her life as she pleased, my Rebecca.
难怪男人不得不杀了她
No wonder a man had to kill her.
你一定很心痛
It must have hurt.
知道你在世上唯一的朋友
Knowing your only friend in the world
把那样的秘密带进坟墓
took a secret like that to her grave.
收拾好你的东西  丹弗斯太太
Pack your bags, Mrs. Danvers.
我要你天黑之前就走人
I expect you gone by nightfall.
伦敦哈利街79b
约·贝克医生合伙诊所
-小姐  有什么事  -真抱歉
- Miss? - Terribly sorry,
我忘拿手提包了
I've left my purse.
你见的是哪位医生  小姐
Who was it you saw, Miss?
约翰·贝克医生
Dr. John Baker.
谢谢
Thank you.
在那儿等着
Wait there.
-贝克医生诊所  -晚上好  塔斯
- Dr. Baker, sir. - Good evening, Tas.
"丹弗斯"
"Danvers."
我见过无数病人
I see so many patients.
我不记得她
I can't remember her.
你看到她的病历也许就能想起来
Maybe it'll come back when you see her file.
先看看病例
It would have been more convenient
自然会更方便
to read the file to begin with.
我们会尽力帮忙
We'll do what we can to help.
不  不该这样
Oh, no. This is not as it should be.
她去哪儿了
Where's she gone now?
谁
Who?
请勿让患者接触
之前在这里的年轻女子
The young woman who was here.
不在这里
It's not here.
我问问我的秘书
I'll have a word with my secretary.
X光结果显示子宫内有根深蒂固的肿块
她可能把病历放错地方了
It's possible she misplaced it.
那个女孩有没有可能离开这里
This girl. Is there any way she could get out of here?
认为是恶性子宫肉瘤
我只是看了  仅此而已
I read it, that's all.
我没改过贝克医生半个字
I haven't changed a word Dr. Baker wrote.
吕蓓卡·丹弗斯
Rebecca Danvers.
是的  现在我想起来了  很可怕的病
Yes, now I remember. Terrible thing.
那不是她的真名
That wasn't her real name.
她也没怀孕
And she wasn't pregnant.
那她为什么要用假名
Then why would she use a false name?
她为什么要大老远跑来伦敦
Why would she come all the way to London
预约你给她看诊
to make an appointment with you
而不找她的家庭医生
and not her family doctor?
或许她不想让家人知道这个噩耗
Perhaps she wanted to spare her family the news.
什么  知道孩子不是她丈夫的吗
That the baby wasn't her husband's?
警长  我不是那种妇科医生
Inspector, I am not that kind of women's specialist.
我不是产科医师
I'm not an obstetrician.
我的专长是肿瘤学
My field is oncology.
我治疗生殖系统的癌症
I treat cancers of the reproductive system.
她肿胀  疲乏
The bloating, the fatigue.
这些都是常见症状
They're common symptoms.
她患了癌症
She had cancer.
她想告诉杰克·费弗尔的就是这事
There's her news for Jack Favell.
这并不能证明她是自杀的
That doesn't prove she killed herself.
她不会想遭受病痛折磨
She wouldn't have wanted to suffer.
没错  她也这么跟我说的
Yes, she told me as much.
她出现症状时已经是晚期
She was very advanced by the time she was symptomatic.
我第一次见她是在四月
Saw her first in April,
到五月时  她显然已经病重得无法医治
by May, it was clear she was too far gone for treatment.
她只剩下几周时间
She only had weeks
并且会遭受巨大痛苦
and the pain would have been considerable.
她如何自尽的
How did she do it?
她把船取出来凿穿
She took out her boat and scuttled it.
然后把自己淹死了
She drowned herself.
你真走运  迈克斯
Stroke of luck for you there, Max.
你一定认为你赢了  对吧
I bet you think you've won, don't you?
也许法律不能惩罚你
Well, maybe the law can't get you.
但我仍然可以
I still can.
你还有别的话想说吗
Is there anything else you want to say?
如果有就赶紧说
If there is, you better say it now.
你知道我最恨她哪一点吗
Do you know what I hate her for most?
她夺走了你的纯真
It's what she's taken from you.
那一去不复返了
It's gone forever.
我所钟爱的那些幽默  朝气  迷惘的神情
That funny, young, lost look I loved so much.
你不再是从前那个女孩了
You're not that person anymore.
别因为这个恨她
Don't hate her for that.
吕
什么东西着火了
What's that burning?
天呐  是曼陀丽庄园
Oh, my God, that's Manderley.
快点  离开那里
Come on! Get away from there.
离开草坪  快走
Get off the lawn! Go! Come on!
离开草坪  弗里思  快离开草坪
Get off the lawn! Frith, get off the lawn!
屋里有多少人  大家都逃出来了吗
How many people are inside? Is everyone out?
我不知道  老爷
I don't know, sir.
你没事吧  发生了什么  克拉丽斯
You all right? What happened, Clarice?
我看见她了
I saw her.
什么意思  你看见谁了
What do you mean? Who did you see?
丹弗斯太太
Mrs. Danvers.
帮帮她
Help her! Help her!
水管在哪儿
Where are the hoses?
她在哪里  她在哪里
Where is she? Where is she!
她去船库了
She went to the boat house.
丹弗斯太太  求求你
Mrs. Danvers! Please!
别站在悬崖边
Please come away.
你叫我帮助你  我这就是在帮你
You asked for my help. Here it is.
丹弗斯太太  求你了
Mrs. Danvers, please.
他杀了我唯一爱过的人
He killed the only person I loved.
我不能让你们夺走曼陀丽庄园
I can't let you have Manderley.
那是属于我们的  你明白吗
It was ours, you see.
你不必这么做
You don't have to do this.
我知道你会支持他
I know you'll stand by him.
但你永远不会知晓幸福的滋味
But you'll never know happiness.
我会的
Yes, I will.
昨晚  我又梦到我去了曼陀丽庄园
Last night, I dreamt I went to Manderley again.
我梦见了丹弗斯太太和吕蓓卡
I dreamt of Mrs. Danvers and of Rebecca.
但今早我醒来后
But this morning I woke up
就把逝者抛诸脑后
and left the dead behind.
我坐在镜子前
And as I sit before the mirror
身处我们在开罗的闷热房间里
in our stuffy little room in Cairo,
这只是其中一站  直到我们找到真正的家
just another stop on our quest to find a real home,
我能看清我现在变成了什么样子
I can see the woman I am now.
我知道我做出了正确决定
And I know that I have made the right decision...
拯救了唯一值得为之赴汤蹈火的东西
to save the one thing worth walking through flames for.
爱
Love.
蝴蝶梦